A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Special Collections Publications FA1395
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Fund for Adult Education (FAE) Publications, 1934-2010; 3
  - An Introduction to Economic Reasoning: Book of Readings, Marshall A. Robinson, Herbert C. Morton, and James D. Calderwood, 1956 (Box 55, Folder 601)
  - Economic Reasoning Study-Discussion Program Promotional Materials, undated (Box 55, Folder 602)
  - Education for a Free Society: Selected Papers on Political and Personal Freedom, the Content of Liberal Learning and the Role of the Teacher in America by Alexander Meiklejohn, 1957 (Box 55, Folder 603)
  - Education for a Free Society Part 2: Selected Papers on Political and Personal Freedom, the Content of Liberal Learning and the Role of the Teacher in America by Alexander Meiklejohn, 1957 (Box 55, Folder 604)
  - P. T. Palgrave's The Golden Treasury of the Best Songs & Lyrical Poems, The Complete Book, Standard and Brought Up to Date by Oscar Williams, Over 600 Great English & American Poems, A Mentor Book, 1956 (Box 55, Folder 605)
  - The Greeks: A Study of the Character and History of an Ancient Civilization, and of the People Who Created It, H. D. F. Kitto, A Pelican Book, 1956 (Box 55, Folder 606)
  - An Introduction to the Humanities Study-Discussion Program Materials information sheet, undated (Box 56, Folder 607)
  - The Ford Foundation in Indonesia: Current Interests, undated (Box 56, Folder 608)
  - The Jeffersonian Heritage: How to Organize a Discussion Group in Your Own Home, undated (Box 56, Folder 609)
  - Jefferson and Our Times: A Series of Study-Discussion Programs Prepared by Dumas Malone, 1955 (Box 56, Folder 610)
  - Jefferson and Our Times, Study-Discussion Program Materials information sheet, undated (Box 56, Folder 611)
  - Jefferson and Our Times: Discussion Leader's Guide, Experimental Discussion Program, Fund for Adult Education, 1954 (Box 56, Folder 612)
  - Art Reproductions to be Used with the Adult Discussion Series, An Introduction to the Humanities (includes some postcards), undated (Box 56, Folder 613)
    56-48-U3
  - Art Reproductions to be Used with the Adult Discussion Series, An Introduction to the Humanities (includes some postcards), undated (Box 56, Folder 614)
  - Thomas Jefferson and Our Times: Adult Discussion Series, 1954 (Box 56, Folder 615)
  - The Jeffersonian Heritage, Edited by Dumas Malone, 1953 (Box 56, Folder 616)
  - Telling the Ford Foundation Story: How We Create Opportunities to Communicate Our Mission, Our Values, and Our Impact (2 copies), 2010 February (Box 56, Folder 617)
  - Legitimacy and Acceptance in a University Milieu: The Problems of Liberal Adult Education, James Carey, Center of the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1959 (Box 56, Folder 618)
  - College Without Classes: Credit Through Examinations in University Adult Education, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1961 (Box 57, Folder 621)
  - A Comparison of the Effectiveness of Adult Residential and Non-Residential Learning Situations, A. A. Lacognata, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1961 (Box 57, Folder 622)
  - Decision Making in the University Evening College: The Role of the Resident Department Chairman, George H. Daigneault, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1963 (Box 57, Folder 623)
  - Evaluating Liberal Adult Education, Harry L. Miller and Christine H. McGuire, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1961 (Box 57, Folder 624)
  - A Report - A Review of 1958: Future Directions of the Center and A Report of Current Activities, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1959 July (Box 57, Folder 625)
  - A Report - Why Students Drop Out: A Study of Evening College Student Motivations, James T. Carey, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1953 (Box 57, Folder 626)
  - A Report - The Changing University: A Report on the Seventh Annual Leadership Conference, Edited by George H. Daigneault, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1959 May (Box 57, Folder 627)
  - A Report - Ability and Achievement of Evening College and Extension Students by Roger DeCrow, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1959 July (Box 57, Folder 628)
  - Reorientation in Labor Education: A Symposium on Liberal Education for Labor in the University, Edited by Frieda H. Goldman, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1962 (Box 57, Folder 629)
  - A Conspectus to the Self-Study Project of University College, The University of Chicago, Edited by Robert M. Roth, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1964 (Box 57, Folder 630)
  - Exploration in Teaching Styles: Report of Preliminary Investigations and Development of Categories, Daniel Soloman and Harry L. Miller, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1961 (Box 57, Folder 631)
  - New Perspectives in University Correspondence Study, Charles Wedemeyer and Gayle B. Childs, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1961 (Box 57, Folder 632)
  - Cumulative Indexes: Association of Evening Colleges Proceedings, 1948-58; National University Extension Association Proceedings, 1915-57, 1960 April (Box 57, Folder 633)
  - Adult Education and Adult Needs, Robert J. Havighurst and Betty Orr, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1956 (Box 57, Folder 634)
  - The Widening Circle of Enriched Ideas and Experience brochure, undated (Box 57, Folder 635)
  - The Literature of Liberal Adult Education, 1945-1957, Compiled by J.D. Mezirow and Dorothea Berry, The Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1960 (Box 57, Folder 636)
  - Continuing Education for Adults, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults at Boston University newsletters no. 68-105, 1965 January-1966 December (Box 58, Folder 637)
  - The Ways of Mankind Essays, Discussion Leaders Material, and Correspondence, 1953 (Box 58, Folder 638)
  - Chicago's TV College: A Report of a Three Year Experiment by the Chicago City Junior College, Benjamin C. Willis, Peter Masiko, Jr., and Clifford G. Erickson, 1960 (Box 58, Folder 639)
  - A Case in Point, Commission on Research and Experimentation, Council for the Advancement of Small Colleges (CASC), undated (Box 58, Folder 640)
  - Certification in Education, Lucien B. Kinney, 1964 (Box 58, Folder 641)
  - Annual Report of The Fund for Adult Education, 1951 (Box 58, Folder 642)
  - Annual Report, The Fund for Adult Education, 1953-1954 (Box 58, Folder 643)
  - Annual Report, The Fund for Adult Education, 1954-1955 (Box 58, Folder 644)
- The Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE) Publications, 1952-1970; 4
  - Report on Activities to Coordinate Programs of Improvement of Physics Teaching, William C. Kelly, 1958 December 18 (Box 58, Folder 645)
  - A Study of the Teaching of Physics by Grant O. Gale, A TV-Film Evaluation Program, 1957-1958, American Institute of Physics, 1958 November (Box 58, Folder 646)
  - Teaching English to Puerto Rican Pupils In Grades 1 and 2, Language Guide Series, The Puerto Rican Study, Board of Education of the City of New York, 1956 (Box 58, Folder 647)
  - Teaching English to Puerto Rican Pupils in Grades 3 and 4, Language Guide Series, The Puerto Rican Study, Board of Education of the City of New York, 1957 (Box 58, Folder 648)
  - Teaching English to Puerto Rican Pupils in Grades 5 and 6, Language Guide Series, The Puerto Rican Study, Board of Education of the City of New York, 1957 (Box 59, Folder 649)
  - Teaching English to Puerto Rican Pupils in the Secondary School, Language Guide Series, The Puerto Rican Study, Board of Education of the City of New York, 1957 (Box 59, Folder 650)
  - A Guide to the Teaching of English to Puerto Rican Pupils, Intermediate Grades, Language Guide Series, Puerto Rican Study, Board of Education City of New York, 1956 (Box 59, Folder 651)
  - A Guide to the Teaching of English to Puerto Rican Pupils in the Junior High Schools (Experimental Edition), Language Guide Series, Puerto Rican Study, Board of Education City of New York, 1955 (Box 59, Folder 652)
  - The Superintendent's Viewpoint on Educational Television, Region I Conference on the National Association of Educational Broadcasters (NAEB), Thomas Alva Edison Foundation, 1959 March (Box 59, Folder 653)
  - Student Responsibility in Higher Education: A Guide to Campus Programming, US National Student Association, Prepared by Willard Johnson and Eleanor Coleman, 1958 (Box 59, Folder 654)
  - Stipends and Spouses: The Finances of American Arts and Science Graduate Students, James A. Davis, 1962 (Box 59, Folder 655)
  - The Step Ahead: Summer Programs for Secondary School Students, Texas Education Agency, 1957 (Box 59, Folder 656)
  - The Teacher and the Taught: Education in Theory and Practice from Plato to James B. Conant, 1963 (Box 59, Folder 657)
  - Student Reactions to Study Facilities with Implications for Architects and College Administrators: A Report to the Presidents of Amherst College, Mount Holyoke College, Smith College, and The University of Massachusetts, 1960 (Box 59, Folder 658)
  - Teacher Supply and Demand in Colleges and Universities: A Study Conducted by Research Division National Education Association, 1957 (Box 59, Folder 659)
  - The Changing School Curriculum, A Report from the Fund for Advancement of Education, 1966 August (Box 60, Folder 660)
  - Four Case Studies of Programed Instruction, 1964 June (Box 60, Folder 661)
  - Copyright and Intellectual Property, Julius J. Marke, 1967 January (Box 60, Folder 662)
  - Decade of Experiment, The Fund for the Advancement of Education, 1951-1961 (Box 60, Folder 663)
  - A Study of the Teaching of Physics by Film and Television, Grant O. Gale, A TV-Film Evaluation Program (1957-1958), American Institute of Physics, 1958 November (Box 60, Folder 664)
  - A Study on the Utilization of Teaching Resources at Westminster College, New Wilmington, Pennsylvania, by the United Presbyterian Board of Christian Education, 1958 (Box 60, Folder 665)
  - Stephens College Educational Report: III - The Stephens College House Plan: Experimentation and Evaluation, Edited by Ralph C. Leydon, Direction of Educational Development, 1966 January (Box 60, Folder 666)
  - 5 Ways to Get More Out of the Books You Read by William J. Reilly (brochure), undated (Box 60, Folder 667)
  - Southern California High School Specialist-Teacher Program, Second Annual Report, 1960-1961 (Box 60, Folder 668)
  - Southern California High School Specialist-Teacher Program, Fourth Annual Report, 1962-1963 (Box 60, Folder 669)
  - New Horizons in Staff Utilization, Prepared for The Commission on the Experimental Study of the Utilization of the Staff in the Secondary School, 1958 January (Box 60, Folder 670)
    Reprinted from the January 1958 issue of The Bulletin, a publication of the National Association of Secondary-School Principals
  - The New College Plan: A Proposal for a Major Departure in Higher Education, 1958 (Box 60, Folder 671)
    Prepared at the request of the Presidents of Amherst College, Mount Holyoke College, Smith College and the University of Massachusetts with the assistance of a grant from the Fund for the Advancement of Education
  - Modernizing State Government: The New York Constitutional Convention of 1967, Proceedings of The Academy of Political Science (APS) Volume XXVIII, Number 3, 1967 January (Box 61, Folder 672)
  - The New York College Proficiency Examination Program (CPEP), The University of the State of New York, The State Education Department/Albany, 1960 November (Box 61, Folder 673)
  - A Minority of One: The Story of the Franklin Junior High School Training Natural Talent Project, 1959-1964 (Box 61, Folder 674)
  - Professional Preparation and Effectiveness of Beginning Teachers, John S. Beery, University of Miami, 1960 (Box 61, Folder 675)
  - Specialized Literature and Reading Skills for the Culturally Disadvantaged, Theo M. Shea, A Project of Saint Louis University and The Fund for the Advancement of Education, 1967 (Box 61, Folder 676)
  - Universities: Commonwealth and American, A Comparative Study, Oliver C. Carmichael - Draft with Edits, 1958 (?) (Box 61, Folder 677, Box 62, Folder 678-679)
    From original folder: To Harper and Brothers - see p. III of preface
  - Progress Report of the Pilot Study in the Preparation of Elementary Teachers, University of Louisville, 1954 September (Box 62, Folder 680)
  - Organizing New York State for Educational Change, Henry M. Brickell, 1961 December (Box 62, Folder 681)
  - Progressing Toward Better Schools: Third Report on Staff Utilization Studies, 1960 January (Box 62, Folder 682)
    Reprinted from the January 1960 issue of The Bulletin, a publication of the National Association of Secondary-School Principals; Prepared for The Commission on the Experimental Study of the Utilization of the Staff in the Secondary School
  - Preparing Administrators: New Perspectives, Edited by Jack Culbertson and Stephen Hencley, The University Council for Educational Administration (UCEA), 1962 (Box 62, Folder 683)
  - A Memo to a College Trustee: A Report on Financial and Structural Problems of the Liberal College, Beardsley Ruml and Donald H. Morrison (2 copies), 1959 (Box 62, Folder 684)
    First Edition, Second Printing and First Edition, Third Printing
  - Report to the Fund for the Advancement of Education, Center for Cooperative Education, Northeastern University, March 1965 - July 1968, 1968 September (Box 63, Folder 685)
  - Report of Paperback Book Project, Atlanta, Georgia, 1967 August (Box 63, Folder 686)
    Sponsored by: The Education Improvement Project, Southern Association of Colleges and Schools; Funded by: The Fund for the Advancement of Education of the Ford Foundation
  - Developing a Theory of Educational Practice for the Elementary School: A Project Conducted Cooperatively by The Norwalk Connecticut Public Schools and New York University Sponsored by The Fund for the Advancement of Education, 1967 June 30 (Box 63, Folder 687-689)
  - The School and College Study of Admission with Advanced Standing, Reports of Committees, 1952-1953, 1953 August (Box 63, Folder 690)
  - A Cooperative Study for the Better Utilization of Teacher Competencies, Second Printed Report, A Description of Teacher Aide Experimentation, Central Michigan College, 1955 (Box 63, Folder 691)
  - Report on Cooperative Education: Summary of the Two-Year National Study of Cooperative Education, Ralph W. Tyler and Annice L. Mills, 1961 (Box 63, Folder 692)
  - The Pugwash Experiment, F. L. Wormald, Association of American Colleges, 1958 (Box 63, Folder 693)
  - Research on Freedom: Report of Dialectical Discoveries and Constructions, May 1953 to October 1954, Volumes I & II, The Institute for Philosophical Research, 1954 December (Box 64, Folder 694)
  - Public Education in the South Today and Tomorrow: A Statistical Survey, Edited by Ernst W. Swanson and John A. Griffin, 1955 (Box 64, Folder 695)
  - The Puerto Rican Study, 1953-1957: A Report on the Education and Adjustment of Puerto Rican Pupils in the Public Schools of the City of New York, J. Cayce Morrison, Board of Education of the City of New York, 1958 (Box 64, Folder 696)
  - A Letter to Friends of Puerto Rican Children, The Puerto Rican Study - newsletter (2 copies), 1955 October 1 (Box 64, Folder 697)
  - The Year-Round Campus Catches On, Sidney G. Tickton, 1963 January (Box 65, Folder 698)
  - Report of Scandinavian Study-Tour: A Preliminary Study of the Educational Systems of Denmark, Finland, Iceland, Norway, and Sweden, World Education Series, Eunice Chapman, 1959 March (Box 65, Folder 699)
  - Continuing Education in Alaska, University of Alaska, 1962 (Box 65, Folder 700)
  - A Report on the Arkansas Experiment in Teacher Education (AETE), 1960 September (Box 65, Folder 701)
  - The Renewal of Catholic Higher Education, Charles E. Ford and Edgar L. Roy, Jr., National Catholic Educational Association, 1968 (Box 65, Folder 702)
  - The Recruitment and Training of Teacher Interns: A Report of the Southern California Teacher Education Project, 1954-1959, C. Edward Meyers, Wendell E. Cannon, D. Welty Lefever, School of Education, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, 1960 (Box 65, Folder 703)
  - Resource Units for Classes with Puerto Rican Pupils in the First - Sixth Grade (Experimental Edition), Resource Unit Series, The Puerto Rican Study, Board of Education, City of New York, 1961 (Box 65, Folder 704-709)
  - Resource Units for Classes with Puerto Rican Pupils, Secondary School Transition Stage, Resource Unit Series, The Puerto Rican Study, Board of Education, City of New York, 1957 (Box 65, Folder 710)
  - Resource Units for Classes with Puerto Rican Pupils, Secondary School Extended-Orientation Stage, Resource Unit Series, The Puerto Rican Study, Board of Education, City of New York, 1961 (Box 66, Folder 711)
  - Resource Units for Classes with Puerto Rican Pupils, Secondary School Orientation Stage, Resource Unit Series, The Puerto Rican Study, Board of Education, City of New York, 1961 (Box 66, Folder 712)
  - Resource Units Suggested for Use in Seventh Grade Classes with Puerto Rican Pupils (Experimental Edition), Resource Unit Series, The Puerto Rican Study, Board of Education, City of New York, 1961 (Box 66, Folder 713)
  - Report to the Faculty of the College of Letters and Science by the Special Committee on Objectives, Programs, and Requirements, College of Letters and Science, University of California, Berkeley, 1957 (Box 66, Folder 714)
  - A Study of Income and Expenditures in Sixty Colleges, Academic Year, 1953-1954, Working Manual, National Federation of College and University Business Officers Associations (Box 66, Folder 715)
  - A Study of Income and Expenditures in Sixty Colleges, A Summary Report: Year 1953-1954 (2 copies) (Box 66, Folder 716-717)
  - A Study on the Utilization of Teaching Resources at Macalester College, St. Paul, Minnesota, United Presbyterian Board of Christian Education, 1959 (Box 66, Folder 718)
  - Continuing Education for Alumni: Report of the Shoreham Conference on Continuing Education for Alumni, Sponsored by the American Alumni Council and The Fund for Adult Education, Robert J. Ahrens, Resolution on Continuing Alumni Education of the American Alumni Council, 1958 (Box 66, Folder 719)
  - The Community Education Project: A Four Year Report, 1952-1956, San Bernardino Valley College, California, 1957 (Box 66, Folder 720)
  - The Initial Teaching Alphabet in Reading Instruction, Lehigh-Bethlehem Evaluation Project on the Use of I.T.A., Comprehensive Final Report, 1967 February (Box 66, Folder 721)
  - An Institutional Self-Study at Arkansas Agricultural and Mechanical College by George S. Reuter, Jr., Director, 1957 (Box 67, Folder 722)
  - Images of the Future: A New Approach in the Secondary School, J. Lloyd Trump, Commission on the Experimental Study of the Staff in the Secondary School, 1959 (Box 67, Folder 723)
  - Report of Educational Television Programs Institute, Television in Education, 1952 April (Box 67, Folder 724)
    A Summary Report, preprinted from the complete proceedings of the Educational Television Programs Institute held at Pennsylvania State College, April 20-24, 1952, Carroll V. Newsom, Director, American Council on Education
  - Investment in Innovation: An Historical Appraisal of the Fund for the Advancement of Education, Paul Woodring, 1970 (Box 67, Folder 725)
  - American Ideas About Adult Education, 1710-1951, Classics in Education No. 2, Edited by C. Hartley Grattan, 1959 (Box 67, Folder 726)
  - Team Teaching in Hawaii's Schools, College of Education, University of Hawaii, 1961 October (Box 68, Folder 727)
  - Tests and Testing: Developing a Program for Testing Puerto Rican Pupils in the New York City Public Schools, Puerto Rican Study Research Report, Board of Education, City of New York, 1959 (Box 68, Folder 728)
  - Learning to Listen: A Handbook for Music, Prepared with the Humanities Staff of the College at the University of Chicago, by Grovesner Cooper, 1957 (Box 68, Folder 729)
  - Team Teaching, Edited by Judson T. Shaplin and Henry F. Olds, Jr., 1964 (Box 68, Folder 730)
  - Financing the College Education of Faculty Children: A Study Conducted by the Teachers Insurance & Annuity Association for the Fund for the Advancement of Education, Francis P. King, 1953 October (Box 68, Folder 731)
  - The Future is Now, The Puerto Rican Study, The Education and Adjustment of Puerto Ricans in New York City, undated (Box 68, Folder 732)
  - Who Uses Our Educated Manpower?: A Survey Report on the Employment of College Alumni, Council for Financial Aid to Education, Inc., 1961 September (Box 68, Folder 733)
  - The First 55, Presented by The Administrative Internship in Secondary School Improvement, A Project of The National Association of Secondary School Principals, J. Lloyd Trump and Lois S. Karasik (2 copies), 1967 (Box 68, Folder 734)
  - Focus on Change: Guide to Better Schools, by J. Lloyd Trump and Dorsey Baynham, 1961 (Box 68, Folder 735)
    Commission on the Experimental Study of the Utilization of the Staff in the Secondary School
  - Financing the College Education of Faculty Children: A Study Conducted by Teachers Insurance & Annuity Association for The Fund for the Advancement of Education, Francis P. King, 1954 (Box 68, Folder 736)
  - A Fourth of a Nation, Paul Woodring, 1957 (Box 69, Folder 737)
  - Genetic Studies of Genius Volume V: The Gifted Group at Mid-Life: Twenty-Five Years' Follow-Up of the Superior Child, 1959 (Box 69, Folder 738)
  - The Higher Learning in America: A Reassessment, Paul Woodring, 1968 (Box 69, Folder 739)
  - Graduate Students Experience at Columbia University, 1940-1956, Hans Rosenhaupt, 1958 (Box 69, Folder 740)
  - 1. Culture in Canada, Edited by Albert A. Shea, Learning for Living, The Canadian Association for Adult Education for The Fund for Adult Education, 1952 (Box 69, Folder 741)
  - High-School Chemistry on Motion Pictures and Filmstrips, Sponsored by the Fund for the Advancement of Education, 1957 July (Box 69, Folder 742)
  - General Education in the Colleges of Arkansas: Arkansas Experiment in Teacher Education, Hoyt Trowbridge, 1958 (Box 69, Folder 743)
  - General Education for Teachers: Report of a Post-Baccalaureate Program Leading to a Master of Science in Education Degree, Pilot Study I, of an Experimental Program in Teacher Education (EPTE), Conducted by Temple University, 1961 (Box 69, Folder 744)
  - The Gifted Child in Portland: A Report of Five Years in Experience in Developing a Program for Children of Exceptional Endowment, Portland Public Schools, Portland, Oregon, 1959 (Box 69, Folder 745)
  - Parent Education Project of the Bloomingdale Family Program, First Annual Report to the Fund for the Advancement of Education, 1965 July 1-1966 June 30 (Box 70, Folder 746)
  - The Negro, The Law, and the Public Schools: A Study of Patterns of Biracial Education in the United States, Preliminary Draft Prepared for The Fund for the Advancement of Education, 1953 October 15 (Box 70, Folder 747)
  - Preliminary Study, Teacher Assistants, Yale-Fairfield Study of Elementary Teaching, Clyde M. Hill, Director, 1954-1958 (Box 70, Folder 748)
  - Yale-Fairfield Study of Elementary Teaching Report, Abridged Edition, 1954-1955, 1956 (Box 70, Folder 749)
  - The Norwalk Plan: A Study Designed to Establish New Careers for Teachers, First Report, Conducted by the Norwalk Board of Education, 1959 July (Box 70, Folder 750)
  - The Norwalk Plan of Team Teaching, Third Report, 1960-1961, Conducted by the Norwalk Board of Education, 1961 October (Box 71, Folder 751)
  - The Norwalk Plan of Team Teaching, Fourth Report, 1961-1962, Conducted by the Norwalk Board of Education (Box 71, Folder 752)
  - Norwalk School Improvement Program, 1962 April-1963 August (Box 71, Folder 753)